

**Email** arikhansylvester@gmail.com

**Address** 

Hinter der Stockmuhle, Freiberg.

Phone

01633731957

Link

https://portfoliosa.herokuapp.com/

#### **Skills**

HTML5

**CSS** 

JavScript

Node.js

React.js

MongoDB

ReactNative

**Project Management** 

TDD

SQL

Angular

Git

### Languages

**English**Native

German

Interme<u>diate</u>

# Sylvester Arikhan

Full-Stack Developer

A Full-Stack Web Developer with experience in JavaScript MERN stack and building responsive Web and mobile Application. To inculcate professional ethics, contribute effectively and productively towards quality service through meticulously planned hard work, keep up team spirit to achieve organizational goals and keep a lasting legacy.

#### Experience

## Junior Developer (Intern)

LocaaTech Lagos Nigeria

Jun 2020 - Present

- Contributing in the development of web apps, using HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- Working along with Senior Developers to solving programming tasks.
- Helped in handling workflow as we progress on the development of applications.

# Working Student

Volkswagen Sachsen GmbH Sachsen

Jun 2020 - Dec 2020

- Receiving deliveries of vehicle parts and preparing them for production line.
- Assembling parts ready to be fitted to vehicle.
- Shaping metal sheets that will make up frame of the vehicle.
- Fixing parts to the frame.

# Assistance Quality Control

AKMA Engineering Nigeria Limited Lagos

Dec 2014 - Jul 2017

- Treatment of water and accessing taste and clarity of drinking water.
- Completed and processed paperwork and reports outlining proper and improper operations.
- Maintained excellent attendance record, consistently arriving to work on time.
- Managed quality assurance program, including on- site evaluations, internal audits, and customer surveys.

### Education

## Full-Stack Developer

Career Foundry Berlin

Mar 2021 - Oct 2021

- Completed a 941 hour full stack development training program under the supervision of industry leading mentors and tutors.
- The project-based program is divided into 2 parts, Introduction to Front-End Development and Full-Stack Immersion.

- Studied and trained through a total of 7 achievements from 60 exercises and 7 projects

### Bachelor of Sciences

**Ambrose Alli University** *Ekpoma/Nigeria* Oct 2010 - Oct 2014

#### **Projects**

A **(Pokedex)** web application, built with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript that loads data from an external API and enables the viewing of data points in detail.

Building the server-side component of a **(movies web application)**. The web application provide users with access to information about different movies, directors, and genres. Users can sign up, update their personal information, and create a list of their favorite movies.

Using React to build the client-side for an application called **(myFlix)** based on its existing server-side code (REST API and database)

A **(MeetApp).** serverless PWA that can display and filter meetup events from the Google calender API. It is developed using Test-Drive-Development techniques to ensure a high test coverage rate.

A **(Chat App)** for mobile devices using React Native. The app provide users with a chat interface and options to share images and their location.

Using Angular to build the client-side for an application called **(myFlix)**, based on its existing server-side code (REST API and database), with supporting documentation.

Certifications & Courses

Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP SAP)

Project Management Professional (PMP)

Residence Permit

Angehöriger Art 10 rl 2004/38/EU. (Gainful employment allowed).